ERICA PHILLIPS

Software Developer

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Coming from a background in various aspects of research, I am driven toward optimization and finding solutions, creatively and through data. I want to make people's lives better and easier, whether that's through being a kind and encouraging teammate, solving complex problems in databases, or making a website easy to use.

CONTACT

845.649.6483 erica-phillips.com ericaphill@gmail.com github.com/ericaphillips www.linkedin.com/in/erica-phillips0

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript, React
- Python, Django
- Git and GitHub
- SQL
- JSON Server

PROJECTS

The Laugh Track

The Laugh Track is an application designed to be a personal organizational tool for comedy fans, with some social aspects. Users can upload comedy specials they have watched and favorite comedians, giving useful information for themselves and others. Users can sort specials and comedians based on a variety of criteria, and users can also view what others have uploaded.

https://github.com/ericaphillips/the-laugh-track-frontend-capstone

- Full CRUD React application using React hooks to manage state
- Styling done in CSS
- Utilizes JSON server for data storage

WasteList

WasteList is an application designed to connect individuals interested in getting a COVID-19 vaccination with nearby pharmacies. At the end of a vaccination day pharmacies often have leftover vaccine doses, and doses have gone to waste around the country. This app is designed to reduce waste and increase vaccinations. hhttps://github.com/ericaphillips/wastelist-

https://github.com/ericaphillips/wastelist-client

- Full CRUD application using React hooks to manage state
- Styling done in CSS and React-Bootstrap
- MVC handled by Python and Django as the backend rest framework

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

A full-time 6 month intensive software development bootcamp focusing on learning through team-based and individual projects to become a full-stack developer

- Created one page applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- Git and gitHub for version control
- Database planning and visualization using entity-relationship diagrams
- Collaorated in remote teams

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Associate

20|20 Research | 2019-2020

- Managed market research projects
- Assisted with market research projects by setting up projects, communicating with clients and participants, solving problems, and recruiting participants
- Programmed surveys in SurveyGizmo, scripting in PHP, Lua, and JavaScript
- Moderated Zoom meetings and provided technical support for clients and participants
- Performed quality control analyses on pre-programmed surveys

Research Assistant

UC Irvine. | 2016 - 2018

- Provided assistant on research being done at UC Irvine in the Psychology and Social Behavior department
- Analyzed data in SPSS and R
- Wrote scholarly findings based on data analyses

Snowboard Instructor

Mountain Creek | 2015-2016

• Taught people of all ages and skill levels how to snowboard using terrain-based learning techniques

EDUCATION HISTORY

Nashville Software School

Certificate, Software Development

Stony Brook University

B.A. Psychology December 2015